Nemat Aloush

A **Data Scientist** (Python, and SQL) with over two years of experience working with international teams. Graduated in the top 10% of the class with a B.Sc. in Software Engineering. Soon to graduate with a M.Sc. in Applied Mathematics and Informatics.

Saint Petersburg, Russia

memat.aloush@gmail.com

in LinkedIn/nemat.aloush

GitHub/nemat.aloush

Portfolio/nemat.aloush

EDUCATION

ITMO University, Master's degree in Applied Mathematics and Informatics – Machine Learning and Big Data Analysis Technologies.

The degree is completely in English

SEP 2021 - JUL 2023

<u>Multivariate Data Analysis Project</u>. Analyzing a real-world dataset by studying univariate and multivariate random variables, sampling, and forecasting using Python.

HIAST Institution, Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

Graduated in the top 10% of the class.

OCT 2015 - SEP 2020

<u>Semantic Search Engine Project</u>. Developed a semantic search engine in English to search among news imported from the BBC. The engine was developed using Java and applying Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval concepts.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Syrian Virtual University, Damascus, Syria — Teacher Assistant

Providing virtual education to students from around the world. APR 2021 - SEP 2021

- Teaching basic concepts in algorithm thinking and C# programming language to first-year students in the Information Technology program.
- Evaluating 120 students' individual final projects.
- Member of a team of two professors and three other engineers.
- Regularly taught the course remotely.

<u>Syriatel Mobile Telecom</u>, Damascus, Syria — *Software Engineer, Student Internship*

A telecommunications company in Syria.

JUL 2019 - SEP 2019

- Developed a <u>Social Network Analysis system</u> in R programming language as a fourth-year academic project. The project served to guide any user with no experience to discover social networks.
- Worked under the supervision of two academic supervisors and one technical supervisor.
- Ranked first in my academic fourth year, based on the grade of the project and other academic courses.

STACK

Proficient: Python, SQL, C#, C++, Java, Pandas, NumPy, Jupyter, GitHub.

Good: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Git, Skearn, SciPy, Keras, TensorFlow.

Familiar: R, Kubernetes, Spark

LANGUAGES

Arabic native
English fluent
German beginner
French beginner
Russian beginner



Talent without Borders.
Imagine Foundation e.V.
joinimagine.org

10/14/2022

Recommendation letter for Nemat Aloush

Dear colleague -

I hope this finds you well.

I'm writing to you to **strongly endorse Nemat Aloush** for a technical role in your company.

We are a social venture that supports young aspiring talents from non-European countries in finding a challenging tech job in Europe or North America. We run a highly selective 4 week digital boot camp for full stack developers, data scientists/engineers and software automation testers. Over the course of the program, we identify candidates whose talent, passion and work ethic significantly stand out from their peers.

Nemat Aloush is an outstanding Data scientist who ranks in the top 10% of our peer group.

English communication Strong – validated in multiple rounds of 1:1 interviews

Technical skills High & up to date – on par with candidates in Germany

Unique qualities Academic excellence (top 10% of class)

EU 'Blue Card' eligibility Yes - Degree needs review - run a quick check via Anabin DB

Maturity Junior – 1 year of work experience

Please feel free to reach out to me personally at <u>johann@joinimagine.org</u> in case of any questions.

Warm regards & herzliche Grüße -

Dr. Johann Daniel Harnoss

JoGun Hary S

Founder & CEO